

Istanbul/Turkey

□ (+90) 537 871 35 93 | wtku@turunc.me | dutku.turunc.me | utkuturunc | utkuturunc | utkuturunc

Summary

Software Engineer of two years with additional three years of experience in full-stack web development from freelance projects.

Most of my professional experience is at a software house, which enabled me to work on several different projects therefore I am experienced and/or familiar with various technologies. I have been working as a software engineer mainly focused on backend development but due to my freelance projects and personal interests in the frontend development technologies, I am also highly fluent in ReactJS and it's ecosystem including React-Router, Redux, GraphQL and RxJS. My preference of JavaScript flavor is Typescript, I am also comfortable with ES6.

Professionally, I have been developing backends in Koa (NodeJS), Play Framework (Scala) and Spring Boot (Kotlin). I have experience in microservices layout. I also have experience in AWS, GCP, Docker and Kubernetes as I've been taking active responsibilities in devops for several projects.

My current technology of choice is Play Framework and I am actively trying to develop a more functional style of programming.

Work Experience

Valensas Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jul. 2016 - Present

- Worked at artificial intelligence projects, focusing on chatbots.
- Designed a chatbot framework that can manage conversation states, execute timed jobs, integrate with other web services, use machine learning and natural language processing in order to understand user input.
- Worked mostly as a Backend Software Engineer, also developed Web UI using ReactJS for chatbot administration feature

Freelance Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Jan. 2013 - Jul. 2016

- Worked on several small to medium scale freelance projects as a full stack developer.
- Stack of choice is NodeJS (Koa) or Play Framework (Scala) + ReactJS with GraphQL.

Techneon Istanbul, Turkey

EMBEDDED SYSTEMS INTERN

Jan. 2016 - Feb. 2016

- Winter Internship on Embedded System Design.
- Designed an energy saving smart electrical outlet.

Huawei Technologies Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

Jul. 2015 - Sep. 2015

- Summer Internship at R&D department.
- Worked on a data mining project using SpringMVC.
- Integrated Swagger into a project that is used for web service discovery.

AVEA (currently Türk Telekom)

Istanbul, Turkey

Jun. 2014 - Aug. 2014

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

- Summer Internship at AveaLabs.
- Developed an admin ui using AngularJS and Django.

Skills

Programming Scala, Java, Typescript, Python, Spark, CoreNLP, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing

Web Development Play Framework, Spring Boot, ReactJS, NodeJS, Redux, GraphQL, Apollo, Koa, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, REST

Electronics SPICE, MagicVLSI, IRSIM, Matlab, Arduino, C, C++, Filter Design, VHDL, Analog Circuit Design, MEMS

Database Redis, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Hibernate

DevOPS AWS, Google Cloud Engine, Docker, Kubernetes, Linux, Microservices

Presentations

Turkey Artificial Intelligence Initiative (turkiye.ai)

Istanbul, Turkey

Oct. 2017 PRESENTER FOR VALENSAS

• A talk about the usage of artificial intelligence in our projects

Education

İTÜ (Istanbul Technical University) (3.95/4)

Istanbul, Turkey

B.S. IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2013

Transferred to Boğaziçi University at the end of the first year

Boğaziçi University (3.24/4)

Istanbul, Turkey

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING

Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2016

- Completed electronics specialization
- · Grade is not inclusive of first year

Projects

Undisclosed P2P Banking Application

Istanbul, Turkey

BACKEND DEVELOPER

Feb. 2018 - Present

- Developed several microservices for a modern peer to peer banking application
- Set up Kubernetes configurations and deployment pipelines.
- · Responsible for core banking and social feeds.
- Project uses Spring Boot and Hibernate for core banking, Scala (Akka) for social feeds

Valensas VoT Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jul. 2016 - Present

- · Valensas VoT is a complete customizable chatbot solution that includes conversation management, natural language processing in English and Turkish, machine learning and scheduled tasks.
- Designed and developed the framework for this project that was used in several other projects.

Akbank Assistant - Akbank Chatbot

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sep. 2017 - May. 2018

- Developed a chatbot for Akbank, one of the largest banks in Turkey.
- The bot can be used to transfer money and pay invoices.
- The project was written as 4 microservices in TypeScript and Scala (Play Framework, Spark and CoreNLP) and deployed to Akbank datacenters on Linux.
- Project has been released with a TV commercial and printed press coverage.

Boti - Turkish Airlines Chatbot

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2017 - Sep. 2017

- Developed a chatbot for Turkish Airlines, a star alliance member and flag carrier airline of Turkey.
- The bot can be used to buy tickets, select seats, check-in, query flight statuses and more.
- The project was written as 4 microservices in TypeScript and Scala (Play Framework, Spark and CoreNLP) and deployed to AWS Elastic Beanstalk.

Hepsichat - Hepsiburada Chatbot

Istanbul, Turkey

Jul. 2016 - Dec. 2016

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Nov. 2016 - Feb. 2017

- Developed a customer support chatbot for the largest e-commerce platform in Turkey, Hepsiburada.
- The chatbot greets users, collects information and solves specific issues, if it cannot resolve the issue it redirects the users to human agents, saving time and resources.
- · The project was written in TypeScript and Scala (Play Framework, Spark and CoreNLP) and deployed to AWS Lambda and AWS Elastic Beanstalk

AskTim - Chatbot Istanbul, Turkey

- Developed a Slack bot that is integrated with several analytics providers such as Mixpanel and Google Analytics.
- The bot is able to process natural language and produce visual reports combining data from different sources.
- The project was written in Scala using Play Framework and CoreNLP and deployed to AWS.